Finding Aid for Mitsui Life Financial Research Center (University of Michigan) records, 1990-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Mitsui Life Financial Research Center (University of Michigan) records 1990-2010
Life Financial Research Center.
3.0 linear feet
2013159 Bimu 2
Research center established in 1990 to encourage and support research in global financial market. Center is part of the Stephen M. Ross School of Business at the University of Michigan. Includes founding documents, annual reports, records of symposiums and lectures, particularly the Mitsui Life Symposium on Global Financial Markets; also photographs and scrapbook.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Material was donated by the Mitsui Life Financial Research Center (Donor no. 10962 ) in July, 2013.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
The Mitsui Life Financial Research Center was established in October 1990 to encourage and support research in global financial markets and to facilitate the international exchange of ideas. The Center was endowed by a $3,000,000 grant from the Mitsui Mutual Life Insurance Company of Japan. The Center rapidly expanded its influence and reputation in the support and dissemination of academic research. In addition to hosting successful and highly publicized academic conferences held in both Ann Arbor and Tokyo, the Center sponsors a distinguished lecture series at the Michigan Business School. Distinguished guest lecturers have included a Nobel Laureate in Economics, as well as prominent academicians, government officials and corporate leaders from Japan, Korea, and the United States. The Distinguished Lectureship is augmented by the Mitsui Life Finance Workshop. The workshops provide a forum for the presentation of current academic research by academicians from leading universities throughout the United States.
The Center is also active in the publication and distribution of faculty research through its active working paper series. Working papers and reprints of published articles are distributed through an extensive mailing list to over 1300 academicians and academic institutions throughout the world. The Center also supports the research of both faculty and Ph.D. students. In recent years the Center has acquired and made available to researchers, financial market and economics databases for Japan, Korea, Hong Kong, Taiwan, Thailand, and emerging markets. Additionally the center has assisted in the acquisition of a database of U.S. initial public offerings. The director of the Center is E. Han Kim.
The Mitsui Center collection, 1990 to 2010, includes some administrative records of the Center, but consists primarily of material to the Mitsui Life Symposium on Global Financial Markets. The records are organized in three series: Administration, Events, and Photographs.
Subjects:
Mitsui Life Financial Research Center.; Michigan Ross School of Business.; International economic relations.; International finance.; Finance.; Markets.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Mitsui Life Financial Research Center.; Michigan Ross School of Business.; International economic relations.; International finance.; Kim, U-jung.; Prahalad, C. K.; Sakata, Koshiro.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Administration
  The Administration series (.5 linear feet) contains annual reports, correspondence, the agreement between the Center and the Ross School of Business, a history of the Center, and information on the Center's relationship with Korea, as well as other administrative material.
  - Advisory Board Meeting, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Agreement with U.M. School of Business, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Annual Activity Report, 1997-1999 (Box 1)
  - Annual Report, 1990-1995 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1998 (Box 1)
  - Council for Better Citizenship Study, 1991 (Box 1)
  - First Center Payment, 1990-1994 (Box 1)
  - History and Start-up Material, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Korean Economic Institute of America, 1995, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Korean Exchange Program, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
  - Korean Foundation, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Media Coverage (Box 1)
- Events
  The Events series (2 linear feet) contains information about the various symposiums and lecture series that the Center has hosted, primarily information from the Mitsui Life Symposium on Global Financial Markets.
  - Mitsui Life Symposium on Global Financial Markets
    - Symposium Nos.. 1-6, 1991-1999, 10 folders (Box 1)
    - Symposium Nos.. 7-13, 2000-2007, 16 folders (Box 2)
    - Symposium Nos.. 15-18, 2008-2010, 9 folders (Box 3)
  - 7th U.S.-Korea Academic Symposium, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Ambassador Lee Hong-Koo Visit, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Distinguished Lecture Series, 1994-1998 (Box 3)
  - Korean Studies Lecture, 1998 (Box 3)
  - Mini-Conferences and Workshops, 1999 (Box 3)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series (.5 linear feet) consists of photographs of Global Financial Market Symposium, U.S.-Korean Academic Symposium, Center faculty and events, and visitors, including visits of Kim Woo-Choong, chairman and founders of Daewoo Corporation, and Koshiro Sakata president of Mitsui Mutual Life Insurance Company.
  - Mitsui Life Symposium
    - Symposium Nos. 1-3, 1991-1994, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Symposium Nos. 7-8, 2000-2002, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Symposium No. 14th (Box 3)
  - 7th U.S.-Korea Academic Symposium, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Chairman Kim Daewoo (Box 3)
  - Phelps Hall Dedication, 1990 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook Material (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, ca. 1993-1998 (Outsized) (Volume 1)